<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Goodroot.ca</title>
    <link>/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Goodroot.ca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Declutter Your Digital Life</title>
      <link>/post/2017/03/17/declutter-your-digital-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/03/17/declutter-your-digital-life/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, I had my life transformed by a silly book about cleaning. It was called The Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up and it was written by tidy-master Marie Kondō. Marie suggests taking a step back from your busy life, breathing deeply, then decluttering your life in one ruthless material purge.
To become happier, more productive, and less stressed, she teaches one how to craft a simplified existence surrounded only by the things that spark joy within.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projecting Management</title>
      <link>/post/2017/03/17/projecting-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/03/17/projecting-management/</guid>
      <description>Communication is an exchange of ideas and emotions. When working remotely, our primary vehicle for communication is text. Is this healthy? We&amp;rsquo;ll look into a few passive aggressive manifestations to better prepare ourselves for the weird feelings Slack might give us. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how we can do better.
You may have heard the adage that: &amp;ldquo;over 90% communication is non-verbal&amp;rdquo;. The original study by Albert Mehrabian describes a 55%/38%/7% formula to describe human communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Remote Job</title>
      <link>/post/2017/02/24/how-to-get-a-remote-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/02/24/how-to-get-a-remote-job/</guid>
      <description>As someone who has hired many-a-folk into remote teams, I am often asked: &amp;ldquo;How do I get a remote job?&amp;rdquo;. Many are inspired by the luxurious, jet-setting allure of the Digital Nomad. Others just want to break away from a commute, escape the drudgery of a typical 9-to-5, and be closer to their families. Whatever your reasons, I hope to help you remote-enable your journey through life.
Working with YC-based start-ups and a couple &amp;lsquo;major&amp;rsquo; technical companies, I have welcomed many into the remote-working world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game University</title>
      <link>/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</guid>
      <description>A new machine sat atop the stairs, on a polished wooden table. The space that stored cabinets stuffed with receipts and documents now played host to a top of the line computer: a plastic-forged modern marvel of technology, infused with whirring sprockets and pulsing with electricity.
I gazed in awe during the machine&amp;rsquo;s unveiling; the cathode ray tube would soon flicker to life for the first time. I was excited, well aware of the digital delights that laid in wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anyone Can Program: As Seen In Pixars Ratatouille</title>
      <link>/post/2015/08/15/anyone-can-program-as-seen-in-pixars-ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/08/15/anyone-can-program-as-seen-in-pixars-ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>When you tumble down the programming rabbit hole, you will notice the effort taken to encourage others to begin their journey into the programmatic arts.
You will see boot camps, offering to turn you into a developer of mythological proportions in just six weeks. You will see thousands of people cruise through the first steps in Codecademy, or Khan Academy.
Stack Overflow, community Slacks, and IRC channels will be loaded with new comers seeking wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>