<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on Goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on Goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Makes</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</guid>
      <description>The brightest people I know practice or learn. Engineering things on the Internet is strange; it&amp;rsquo;s a new frontier. In order to feel aware of the web&amp;rsquo;s current state, through surprise blockchain forking, political revolts on social media, studious machine intelligence, new web frameworks and morphing server architecture, there are countless unrelenting streams of which to be mindful. It is folly to dream of understanding even a fraction of our beloved and capable global network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hockey and Roles</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 13:56:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>Hockey is a beautiful sport. Like many younglings who were born in Western Canada, I was raised in part by hockey rinks. Not long after becoming sufficient in tippy baby-walking, I was outside in the deep cold of an Albertan winter with blades strapped to my feet. Little did I know that the sport of hockey would teach me some of the most valuable life lessons and become an integral aspect of my character and contribute to my successes in technical teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Vinyl</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>My ears can hear whatever they want. There’s a magical program within my computer and when I explore it every composition becomes mine. It makes lists for me, using heuristics to determine what I’d like to listen to. It’s often right. Music is beautiful. Music is on rails. A part of music is dead.
Every song is sucked into an algorithm. It’s spliced into a thousand pieces, its beating heart counted to assess time signature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks Are Bad For You</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, my parents painted an intriguing picture of life after sprouting into adulthood. “I was out of the house at 18!”, my father would remind me. Having now grown well past the age that my parents were when they flew from their nests… then owned their first home… then had children… I feel that living in a one-bedroom apartment with questionable asset accumulating potential and no seedlings makes me look soft by comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>