<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on Goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on Goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest Well, Dr. Paul Roberts</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/02/rest-well-dr-paul-roberts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/02/rest-well-dr-paul-roberts/</guid>
      <description>Today I am saddened to hear about the passing of Dr. Paul Roberts. Paul had a significant impact on my life. As 2017 opened up, I found myself at a cross-roads. All this technical skill, all these offers to further technology for technologies sake. Where&amp;rsquo;s the spirit? What&amp;rsquo;s the point?
A door opened up to me after a brilliant blog post compelled me to reach out to its author. My plea for guidance led me to the Alianza Arkana, a non-profit working with the indigenous Shipibo people and the plant medicines of the Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Opinion on Opinions</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/23/an-opinion-on-opions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/23/an-opinion-on-opions/</guid>
      <description>People seem uncomfortable having opinions. I’ve had people tell me with pride that they have weak, weakly held opinions. I&amp;rsquo;ve had others boast that they hold no opinions of any kind. Strong opinions are good and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having them.
 “All opinions are not equal. Some are a very great deal more robust, sophisticated and well supported in logic and argument than others.” ― Douglas Adams
 An opinion is not a fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Game on Earth</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/21/the-best-game-on-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/21/the-best-game-on-earth/</guid>
      <description>Within every cold Canadian community, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an outdoor rink. It is upon these frigid slabs of ice where The Dream is born. These cold, snowy rinks are our churches. They are our playgrounds. When the greats lace up their boots and dazzle the masses, their glory echoes in renactment across all of our ice surfaces. No game is more deserving of this immortal treatment than the gold medal game of Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s 2010 Winter Olympics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Makes</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</guid>
      <description>The brightest people I know practice or learn. Engineering things on the Internet is strange; it&amp;rsquo;s a new frontier. It is folly to hope to understand even a fraction of our beloved and capable global network. In the tangle of all these topics to practice, what kind of patterns are we imprinting?
This weekend, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned the basics of Ruby; next weekend, as per usual, you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hockey and Roles</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 13:56:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>Hockey is a beautiful sport. Like many younglings who were born in Western Canada, I was raised in part by hockey rinks. Not long after becoming sufficient in tippy baby-walking, I was outside in the deep cold of an Albertan winter with blades strapped to my feet. Little did I know that the sport of hockey would teach me some of the most valuable life lessons and become an integral aspect of my character and contribute to my successes in technical teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Vinyl</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>My ears can hear whatever they want. There’s a magical program within my computer and when I explore it every composition becomes mine. It makes lists for me, using heuristics to determine what I’d like to listen to. It’s often right. Music is beautiful. Music is on rails. A part of music is dead.
Every song is sucked into an algorithm. It’s spliced into a thousand pieces, its beating heart counted to assess time signature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks Are Bad For You</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, my parents painted an intriguing picture of life after sprouting into adulthood. “I was out of the house at 18!”, my father would remind me. Having now grown well past the age that my parents were when they flew from their nests… then owned their first home… then had children… I feel that living in a one-bedroom apartment with questionable asset accumulating potential and no seedlings makes me look soft by comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>