<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Game on Earth</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/21/the-best-game-on-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/21/the-best-game-on-earth/</guid>
      <description>Within every cold Canadian community, you&amp;rsquo;ll find an outdoor rink. It is upon these frigid slabs of ice where The Dream is born. These cold, snowy rinks are our churches. They are our playgrounds. When the greats lace up their boots and dazzle the masses, their glory echoes in renactment across all of our ice surfaces. No game is more deserving of this immortal treatment than the gold medal game of Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s 2010 Winter Olympics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Makes</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/20/practice-makes/</guid>
      <description>The brightest people I know practice or learn. Engineering things on the Internet is strange; it&amp;rsquo;s a new frontier. It is folly to hope to understand even a fraction of our beloved and capable global network. In the tangle of all these topics to practice, what kind of patterns are we imprinting?
This weekend, you&amp;rsquo;ve learned the basics of Ruby; next weekend, as per usual, you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hockey and Roles</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 13:56:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/07/hockey-and-roles/</guid>
      <description>Hockey is a beautiful sport. Like many younglings who were born in Western Canada, I was raised in part by hockey rinks. Not long after becoming sufficient in tippy baby-walking, I was outside in the deep cold of an Albertan winter with blades strapped to my feet. Little did I know that the sport of hockey would teach me some of the most valuable life lessons and become an integral aspect of my character and contribute to my successes in technical teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Vinyl</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/07/17/digital-vinyl/</guid>
      <description>My ears can hear whatever they want. There’s a magical program within my computer and when I explore it every composition becomes mine. It makes lists for me, using heuristics to determine what I’d like to listen to. It’s often right. Music is beautiful. Music is on rails. A part of music is dead.
Every song is sucked into an algorithm. It’s spliced into a thousand pieces, its beating heart counted to assess time signature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declutter Your Digital Life</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/03/17/declutter-your-digital-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/03/17/declutter-your-digital-life/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, I had my life transformed by a silly book about cleaning. It was called: The Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up and it was written by tidying Marie Kondō. Marie suggests taking a step back from your busy life, breathing deeply, then decluttering your life in one ruthless material purge.
To become happier, more productive, and less stressed, she teaches one how to craft a simplified existence surrounded only by the things that spark joy within.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projecting Management</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/03/17/projecting-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/03/17/projecting-management/</guid>
      <description>Communication is an exchange of ideas and emotions. When working remotely, our primary vehicle for communication is text. Is this healthy? We’ll look into a few passive aggressive manifestations to better prepare ourselves for the weird feelings Slack might give us. Then, we’ll see how we can do better.
You may have heard the adage that: “over 90% communication is non-verbal”. The original study by Albert Mehrabian describes a 55%/38%/7% formula to describe human communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Astral</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I devoured fiction. Quality fiction, perhaps not, but my imagination received stimulation none-the-lesser. If, within these novels, I found something that sparked my spirit I could then head to the computer to let my mind run, wild and deep, into the unknown. There was a webpage for everything one could dream of.
As a youth, I enjoyed the abstract. The more bizarre and uncommon the plot-line, the more I longed to sink my teeth into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game University</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</guid>
      <description>A new machine sat atop the stairs, on a polished wooden table. The space that stored cabinets stuffed with receipts and documents now played host to a top of the line computer: a plastic-forged modern marvel of technology, infused with whirring sprockets and pulsing with electricity.
I gazed in awe during the machine’s unveiling; the cathode ray tube would soon flicker to life for the first time. I was excited, well aware of the digital delights that laid in wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2016/03/22/after-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2016/03/22/after-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>One year ago, clothes were jammed into a backpack and a plane ticket was purchased for Iquitos, Peru. In the Amazon jungle, I spent a week with Shamans drinking Ayahuasca. My life has transformed. I am going to share with you my experiences re-integrating back into life after Ayahuasca.
 “Life lived in the absence of the psychedelic experience that primordial shamanism is based on is life trivialized, life denied, life enslaved to the ego.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks Are Bad For You</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/11/15/social-networks-are-bad-for-you/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, my parents painted an intriguing picture of life after sprouting into adulthood. “I was out of the house at 18!”, my father would remind me. Having now grown well past the age that my parents were when they flew from their nests… then owned their first home… then had children… I feel that living in a one-bedroom apartment with questionable asset accumulating potential and no seedlings makes me look soft by comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Who Drank Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘90s, everyone was weird. The weirdest among us shuffled off the coil of reality entirely. We were the age-less, culture-less, state-less, God-less generation raised by the Internet… which is to say, we were raised by each other.
The reason for departure differs from person to person: Your parents fought. You had an unusual face or were unsightly. You had weird hair or were full of too many idiosyncrasies. You wanted to learn the ways of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Buddies</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</guid>
      <description>It was 13 years ago when Whitethumbs and I first met, waging virtual war late at night within a crowded voice chat server. We were both young. Myself, 13. Whitethumbs, 14. We both had a passion for competitive gaming. We made fast friends, as we were both goofy and talkative. Little did I know the impact this friendship would have on my life.
After a joyful, silly night of gaming began to wind down, we decided we should exchange contact information to play again another night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>