<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistresses</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/12/04/mistresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/12/04/mistresses/</guid>
      <description>two mistresses life and death one wants what I have the other my breath
who is who? which loves me? feels like they’re above me? will it be that will judge me?
sisters, so similar they love my spirit want to hear it be near it
life listens, she speaks she does so gracefully ever patiently ever wakefully
wake up lumpy one day caught, now death’s say pray come what may</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fell</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/07/25/fell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/07/25/fell/</guid>
      <description>Oh no! Your browser does not support the audio element.   Headphones recommended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CORVID</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/06/20/corvid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/06/20/corvid/</guid>
      <description>There is a pandemic. I am asked to stay within my home. It is different but not different: I am asked to avoid the market, travel, time with friends and to keep my distance from other people. People are scared, but outside the birds seem unbothered.
The days blur together and it is weeks and a month and more. My alarm goes off and it is hard to get up. It takes all of my will and strength to ignore the fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirit</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/25/spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/25/spirit/</guid>
      <description>I love my life  I love my life 
I love my life  I&amp;rsquo;m not scared anymore  And I happily look forward  To the things I have in store</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/20/fly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/20/fly/</guid>
      <description>Oh no! Your browser does not support the audio element.   Headphones recommended!
I return to my apartment on the darkest of all days. It is home and on the ground level, although it does not get much sunlight. My desk is feet from the back door. On it sits three 23&amp;rdquo; monitors and mounted upon the wall is another gigantic pane of glowing black glass. Powering these black mirrors are three computer towers and one flat rack server and they all greet me with a gentle hum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thinker of Tender Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/03/27/the-thinker-of-tender-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/03/27/the-thinker-of-tender-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It struck me as true  as just the way that it goes  for the path that I saw  was not the one that I chose
Yet something changed  somewhere sometime  now life is all flowers  and everything&amp;rsquo;s fine
So take a deep breath  and wait just a bit  for soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see  they&amp;rsquo;re quite full of it!
Your heart will get bigger  your flowers will grow  your seedlings will blossom  and life will just flow</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/12/01/interpolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/12/01/interpolation/</guid>
      <description>I was behind the wall, but the bullet went through my head anyways. Alas, a server determined that the reality on my screen was not the one that it would carry forward to consensus. On my screen, I was safe behind a wall. Yet on my adversaries screen, I was vulnerable, out in the open, and so I was killed. That is the story the server told, the one it took to consensus, the one that it interpreted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Deep Work</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/05/04/on-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/05/04/on-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>Vacation reading is my favourite. When commitments disappear and the pace of life slows down, there are few things more rewarding than diving into new ideas. The ideas of this vacation came from Deep Work by Cal Newport, but they were not so new.
 &amp;ldquo;Deep work is the ability to focus without distraction on a cognitively demanding task. It&amp;rsquo;s a skill that allows you to quickly master complicated information and produce better results in less time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Boot Loader</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 19:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</guid>
      <description>“A year spent in artificial intelligence is enough to make one believe in God.” —Alan Perlis, first recipient of the Turing Award
 I fear no consciousness that will surpass us. We will program allies in our image and with them accomplish all that we desire, be that our own death or enrichment. But we should not be so quick to concede the mantel of “supremacy” to a &amp;ldquo;higher intelligence&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Law Is Real</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</guid>
      <description>Conway&amp;rsquo;s Law was first articulated in 1967 by computer programmer Melvin Conway and within it holds the potential for a radical leap forward in the development of complex programmatic systems:
 “organizations which design systems … are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations.”
 Proving the Law In 2011, Harvard business school published a paper: Exploring the Duality between Product and Organizational Architectures: A Test of the “Mirroring” Hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veganism</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</guid>
      <description>I grew up on the Canadian prairies. As early as the first grade, we had milk day. Each student took a form to their parents and filled out which milk they would receive the following week. Chocolate milk? White milk? One carton? Two cartons?
Next week arrived and the milk cart visited each student. It delivered fresh, cold milk and a bag full of colourful trinkets and stickers. The most famous sticker could be seen attached to car bumpers throughout the city: I &amp;lt;3 Alberta Beef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice Dead</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</guid>
      <description>When I was done dying, my conscious regained So I began the struggle, a nothingness strained - Dan Deacon I was the class clown of the third grade. You could not convince me to sit still. I would do antyhing to make people laugh, to joke, make a silly noise or a do funny impression. But when I changed schools in grade four, all of that changed. And so, this is a story of my two deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glass</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/05/23/glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/05/23/glass/</guid>
      <description>Oh, the Internet. Its borderless edges, unrelenting novelty, and limitless supply of companions won my heart and captivated my imagination. It is heralded as the greatest collaborative engineering effort in human history. But it is much more than that. It is the mirror within which we see our reality and the final platform for our conflicts and outrage that will rocket us towards spiritual evolution.
Today the Internet is tidy chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeds</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</guid>
      <description>You have applied Shamanism, but no one would have told you that’s what it was. Yet there are at least two Shamanic methods of consciousness exploration that people often experience. The first is lucid dreaming.
 “Shamanism is a practice that involves a practitioner reaching altered states of consciousness in order to perceive and interact with a spirit world and channel these transcendental energies into this world.” - Shamanism, wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Astral</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I devoured fiction novels. Something within them sparked my spirit. I would take their inspiration to my other salvation, the computer, and let my mind run, wild and deep, into the unknown. There was a webpage for every thing one could dream. And I had wild dreams.
I enjoyed the abstract. The more bizarre and uncommon the plot-line, the more I longed to sink my teeth into it. One of the many series of abstract children&amp;rsquo;s fiction I consumed was titled: The Zack Files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Who Drank Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘90s, everyone is weird. We are the age-less, culture-less, state-less, God-less generation being raised by the Internet… which is to say, we are raising each other. And the weirdest among us fall into strange places.
As for why, the reasons differ: fighting parents, an unusual or unsightly face, too much time, not enough attention, an odd mind, strange hair or too many idiosyncrasies. Some just want to learn the ways of technology and reap its benefits and some just want to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Buddies</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</guid>
      <description>It was 13 years ago when Whitethumbs and I first met, waging virtual war late at night within a crowded voice chat server. We were both young. Myself, 13. Whitethumbs, 14. We both had a passion for competitive gaming. We made fast friends, as we were both goofy and talkative. Little did I know the impact this friendship would have on my life.
After a night of gaming began to wind down, we decided we should exchange contact information to play again another night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>