<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microdosing on Goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/categories/microdosing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microdosing on Goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/categories/microdosing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Microdosing Affect</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/27/microdosing-affect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/27/microdosing-affect/</guid>
      <description>0: Prologue 1: Baseline 2. Affect  Today is day 15. In my first two entries, I strayed away from discussing how I feel. The placebo effect is potent; I was concerned that the novelty of the experience would sway my interpretation. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous two entries, dosing takes place every third evening. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to get roll into the affectual response to Psilocybe semilanceata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microdosing Baseline</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/15/microdosing-baseline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/15/microdosing-baseline/</guid>
      <description>0: Prologue 1: Baseline  It takes a certain oddness to ingest a psychedelic mushroom every third evening. Looking at the studies and reading the anecdotes of others who have embraced the weirdness, microdosing appears an alluring offer. When you apply outside perception of the experiences, things get dicey. I&amp;rsquo;d like to speak more on that, then get into the work done to establish a baseline before under-taking this experiment; after-all, if you&amp;rsquo;re going to do something people think is silly or even dangerous, you might as well document your experiences and explain yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microdosing Prologue</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/12/microdosing-prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/08/12/microdosing-prologue/</guid>
      <description>0: Prologue 1: Baseline  Today, I embark on a partnership. For the foreseeable future, I will be taking 0.2 grams of Psilocybe semilanceata mushrooms every third evening. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share why I&amp;rsquo;ve begun this adventure, what I hope to achieve, and document my experiences living a modern life, working in a fast-paced tech start-up. My intention is to write an update once per week, observing and describing the short and long-term impact of a softening, Psilocybin-infused consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>