<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spirituality on Goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/categories/spirituality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spirituality on Goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/categories/spirituality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Astral</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I devoured fiction. Quality fiction, perhaps not, but my imagination received stimulation none-the-lesser. If, within these novels, I found something that sparked my spirit I could then head to the computer to let my mind run, wild and deep, into the unknown. There was a webpage for everything one could dream of.
As a youth, I enjoyed the abstract. The more bizarre and uncommon the plot-line, the more I longed to sink my teeth into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2016/03/22/after-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2016/03/22/after-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>One year ago, clothes were jammed into a backpack and a plane ticket was purchased for Iquitos, Peru. In the Amazon jungle, I spent a week with Shamans drinking Ayahuasca. My life has transformed. I am going to share with you my experiences re-integrating back into life after Ayahuasca.
 “Life lived in the absence of the psychedelic experience that primordial shamanism is based on is life trivialized, life denied, life enslaved to the ego.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Who Drank Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘90s, everyone was weird. The weirdest among us shuffled off the coil of reality entirely. We were the age-less, culture-less, state-less, God-less generation raised by the Internet… which is to say, we were raised by each other.
The reason for departure differs from person to person: Your parents fought. You had an unusual face or were unsightly. You had weird hair or were full of too many idiosyncrasies. You wanted to learn the ways of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>