<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 21:14:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Deep Work</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/05/04/on-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/05/04/on-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>Vacation reading is my favourite. When commitments disappear and the pace of life slows down, there are few things more rewarding than diving into new ideas. And ideas of this vacation was Deep Work by Cal Newport but they were not so new.
 &amp;ldquo;Deep work is the ability to focus without distraction on a cognitively demanding task. It&amp;rsquo;s a skill that allows you to quickly master complicated information and produce better results in less time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Boot Loader</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 19:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</guid>
      <description>“A year spent in artificial intelligence is enough to make one believe in God.” —Alan Perlis, first recipient of the Turing Award.
 The machines are coming and we will all perish. Artificial intelligence, cognitive computing and machine learning foreshadow our godliness. From the code, we will summon beings that will surpass our own intelligence. And we are warned that we will be overthrown and that we should fear these agents of our destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Law Is Real</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</guid>
      <description>Some ideas shine with truth. One such idea was articulated in 1967 by computer programmer Melvin Conway:
 “organizations which design systems … are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations.”
 It is often found in good humour: the system is a mess and the people who made it are a mess. Haha &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s Conway&amp;rsquo;s Law for you! Joking aside, within it holds the potential for a radical leap forward in the development of complex programmatic systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veganism</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</guid>
      <description>I grew up on the Canadian prairies. As early as the first grade, we had milk day. Each student took a form to their parents and filled out which milk they would receive the following week. Chocolate milk? White milk? One carton? Two cartons?
Next week arrived and the milk cart visited each student. It delivered fresh, cold milk and a bag full of colourful trinkets and stickers. The most famous sticker could be seen attached to car bumpers throughout the city: I &amp;lt;3 Alberta Beef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice Dead</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</guid>
      <description>When I was done dying, my conscious regained So I began the struggle, a nothingness strained - Dan Deacon  This is a story of my two deaths. Growing up, I thrice relocated: kindergarten, grade four and grade nine. Each move required that I reinvent my character. Traumatic perhaps, but not yet one of my deaths. I was much alive!
I was the class clown of the third grade. You could never coax me into being still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeds</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</guid>
      <description>“It is the mark of an educated mind to be able to entertain a thought without accepting it.” ― Aristotle
 You have applied Shamanism before, I am sure of it. But no one would have told you that’s what it was. And so the question becomes, what is Shamanism? If you ask Wikipedia, it will tell you that….
“Shamanism is a practice that involves a practitioner reaching altered states of consciousness in order to perceive and interact with a spirit world and channel these transcendental energies into this world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Word: Opinion</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/23/power-word-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/02/23/power-word-opinion/</guid>
      <description>Words have power. And we can lose control of words. They can spiral out of control, becoming vast and overwhelming abstractions. These abstractions, through misunderstanding and careless use, then have a profound impact on the world around us. This is series looks at a word and then hopes to reduce it back to reality. This post looks at the word: opinion.
Three definitions of opinion:
  a view, judgment, or appraisal formed in the mind about a particular matter belief stronger than impression and less strong than positive knowledge a formal expression of judgment or advice by an expert   People seem uncomfortable having opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Astral</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I devoured fiction. Within these novels I found something that sparked my spirit. I would then head to the computer to let my mind run, wild and deep, into the unknown. There was a webpage for every thing one could dream.
I enjoyed the abstract. The more bizarre and uncommon the plot-line, the more I longed to sink my teeth into it. One of the many series of abstract children&amp;rsquo;s fiction I consumed was titled: The Zack Files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Who Drank Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘90s, everyone was weird. The weirdest among us shuffled off the coil of reality entirely. We were the age-less, culture-less, state-less, God-less generation raised by the Internet… which is to say, we were raised by each other.
The reason for departure differs from person to person. Your parents fought. You had an unusual face or were unsightly. You had weird hair or were full of too many idiosyncrasies. You wanted to learn the ways of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Buddies</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</guid>
      <description>It was 13 years ago when Whitethumbs and I first met, waging virtual war late at night within a crowded voice chat server. We were both young. Myself, 13. Whitethumbs, 14. We both had a passion for competitive gaming. We made fast friends, as we were both goofy and talkative. Little did I know the impact this friendship would have on my life.
After a night of gaming began to wind down, we decided we should exchange contact information to play again another night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>