<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on goodroot</title>
    <link>https://goodroot.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on goodroot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://goodroot.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spirit</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/25/spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/25/spirit/</guid>
      <description>I love my life  I love my life 
I love my life  I&amp;rsquo;m not scared anymore  And I happily look forward  To the things I have in store</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/20/fly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/04/20/fly/</guid>
      <description>Oh no! Your browser does not support the audio element.   I return to my apartment on the darkest of all days. It is home and on the ground level, although it does not get much sunlight. My desk is feet from the back door. On it sits three 23&amp;rdquo; monitors and mounted upon the wall is another gigantic pane of glowing black glass. Powering these black mirrors are three computer towers and one flat rack server and they all greet me with a gentle hum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thinker of Tender Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/03/27/the-thinker-of-tender-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2020/03/27/the-thinker-of-tender-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It struck me as true  as just the way that it goes  for the path that I saw  was not the one that I chose
Yet something changed  somewhere sometime  now life is all flowers  and everything&amp;rsquo;s fine
So take a deep breath  and wait just a bit  for soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see  they&amp;rsquo;re quite full of it!
Your heart will grow bigger  your flowers will show  your seedlings will blossom  and then they&amp;rsquo;ll all know</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolation</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/12/01/interpolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2019/12/01/interpolation/</guid>
      <description>I was behind a wall but the bullet went through my head anyways. A server determined that the reality on my screen was not the one that it would carry forward to consensus. On my screen I was safe behind a wall, yet on my adversaries screen I was vulnerable, out in the open, and so I was killed. That is the story the server told.
 &amp;ldquo;The introduction of lag compensation allows for each player to run on his or her own clock with no apparent latency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Boot Loader</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 19:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/12/22/biological-boot-loader/</guid>
      <description>“A year spent in artificial intelligence is enough to make one believe in God.” —Alan Perlis, first recipient of the Turing Award.
 We have not yet entered the era of the conscious machine. We are nowhere near electronic intelligence. We may never see it. Instead we build sophisticated applications that mirror the logical and rational frameworks inherited from their programmers.
Applications make decisions based on available data. They may have room to analyze and interpret, but these interpretations are methods born from an existing framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Law Is Real</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/10/13/practicality-metaphysics-conways-law/</guid>
      <description>Some ideas shine with truth. One such idea was articulated in 1967 by computer programmer Melvin Conway:
 “organizations which design systems … are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations.”
 It is often found in good humour: the system is a mess and the people who made it are a mess. Haha &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s Conway&amp;rsquo;s Law for you! Joking aside, within it holds the potential for a radical leap forward in the development of complex programmatic systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veganism</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/09/16/veganism/</guid>
      <description>I grew up on the Canadian prairies. As early as the first grade, we had milk day. Each student took a form to their parents and filled out which milk they would receive the following week. Chocolate milk? White milk? One carton? Two cartons?
Next week arrived and the milk cart visited each student. It delivered fresh, cold milk and a bag full of colourful trinkets and stickers. The most famous sticker could be seen attached to car bumpers throughout the city: I &amp;lt;3 Alberta Beef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice Dead</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/07/29/twice-dead/</guid>
      <description>When I was done dying, my conscious regained So I began the struggle, a nothingness strained - Dan Deacon I was the class clown of the third grade. You could never coax me into sitting still. I would leap to make people laugh, to joke, make a silly noise or a do funny impression. But when I changed schools in grade four, that changed. This is a story of my two deaths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeds</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2018/03/06/seeds/</guid>
      <description>You have applied Shamanism, but no one would have told you that’s what it was. Yet there are at least two Shamanic methods of consciousness exploration that people often experience. The first is lucid dreaming.
 “Shamanism is a practice that involves a practitioner reaching altered states of consciousness in order to perceive and interact with a spirit world and channel these transcendental energies into this world.” - Shamanism, wikipedia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Astral</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/20/do-the-astral-plane/</guid>
      <description>Growing up, I devoured fiction. Within these novels I would often find something that would spark my spirit. I would then take that inspiration to the computer and let my mind run, wild and deep, into the unknown. There was a webpage for every thing one could dream. And I had wild dreams.
I enjoyed the abstract. The more bizarre and uncommon the plot-line, the more I longed to sink my teeth into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Game University</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2017/01/17/video-game-university/</guid>
      <description>I have a deep love and respect for video games. It was a passion developed from growing up glued to a Gameboy. And why not? Games provided a thrill, a challenge and hours of blissful amusement. They were magical contraptions, capable of sating my demanding and hyper-active mind.
Digital escapades were a part of our family legacy: “Remember the time Kellen brought his Gameboy to hockey practice, and sat on the bench playing it instead of skating on the ice?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Who Drank Ayahuasca</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/03/15/the-hacker-who-drank-ayahuasca/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘90s, everyone was weird. We were the age-less, culture-less, state-less, God-less generation raised by the Internet… which is to say, we were raised by each other. And the weirdest among us fell into strange places.
As for why, the reason would differ: fighting parents, an unusual or unsightly face, too much time, not enough attention, an odd mind, strange hair or too many idiosyncrasies. Some wanted to learn the ways of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Buddies</title>
      <link>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goodroot.ca/post/2015/02/20/gaming-buddies/</guid>
      <description>It was 13 years ago when Whitethumbs and I first met, waging virtual war late at night within a crowded voice chat server. We were both young. Myself, 13. Whitethumbs, 14. We both had a passion for competitive gaming. We made fast friends, as we were both goofy and talkative. Little did I know the impact this friendship would have on my life.
After a night of gaming began to wind down, we decided we should exchange contact information to play again another night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>